Iosif Vigh

Senior Software Engineer

London, UK

Github: iosifv in LinkedIn: iosifv 🚵 StackOverflow: iosifv

I am a Senior Software Engineer with extensive experience in developing end-to-end projects using Node.js and Laravel. I prioritise writing clean, maintainable code to ensure ease of maintenance and quick onboarding for junior developers. With a natural curiosity and a commitment to continuous learning, I am always exploring new technologies and methodologies to enhance my skills and contribute effectively to my team and stakeholders. I'm currently working on an open-source personal learning project using T3Stack with NextJS, tRPC, Drizzle ORM and Clerk while deploying to Vercel with Github Actions.

SKILLS

Languages	Frameworks		Dev-Ops	
Node.js Javascript	Laravel Express	Serverless	AWS Terraform	CI/CD
Typescript PHP Solidity	Hardhat		Github Actions	Vercel
bash			Docker	

WORK EXPERIENCE (7)

Aug 2018 - Current

Contractor Software Engineer at Casa4 - own LTD (London, UK)

Provided contractor services through my own LTD, Casa4, in between other roles. The following is a list of the most notable projects, specializing in Laravel and Node.js. Involved both in team-based development and solo application building from design to deployment and maintenance.

- Artetra (NodeJS, React, ThreeJS, Solidity, Hardhat, Express, Postgres, MongoDB, AWS, Docker)
 As an acting CTO, I was responsible with converting business requirements into project features by overseeing the application architecture. I managed a team of 3-4 developers and provided them with necessary assistance.
- ElectroRent (Laravel, MySQL)
 - Developed and maintained Laravel code to fix bugs and add new features for a tool-renting platform.
- Aliat Optic (NodeJS, Serverless Framework, Lambda, DynamoDB, AWS, MySQL, Laravel, DigitalOcean)
 Designed and developed an invoicing app, integrating external FTP data via AWS Lambda and DynamoDB.
 This application was successfully used in production for about 3 years with minimal maintenance, demonstrating reliability and efficiency.
- Hurlingham Club (Laravel, Laravel Forge, Laravel Envoyer, MySQL, AWS, Docker)
 Led the migration of systems to internal servers, resolving various DevOps issues.
- TicketTailor (PHP, MySQL, sqlite)
 Improved the API of a large ticketing application by fixing bugs and adding new features.

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

Software Engineer at True Compliance (London, UK)

Contributed to the development of a cloud-based compliance management system, enhancing compliance tracking and reporting capabilities.

- Developed the main API of the system and contributed to designing the ecosystem's serverless architecture, leading to a robust and scalable solution.
- Created a reporting application that enabled non-technical stakeholders to preview any key metrics.
- Also built a bespoke real-time caching system that stores processed relational data in a NoSQL database. The purpose of this was to vastly increase the speed of the system and reduce the load on the database.
- → Technologies: Laravel, Laravel Vapor, AWS, VueJS, Node.js, Serverless Framework, CLI, Bash

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Software Engineer at Skin Analytics (London, UK)

Designed and developed main applications and maintained AWS infrastructure, contributing to the company's mission of improving skin health.

- Led the migration from a NoSQL database to a relational database, resulting in an 11x speed increase without affecting the frontend or user experience.
- Green Handwight Street, Street Street, Street Street, S

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

Application Developer / Dev-Ops at Woooba (London, UK)

Sole Backend Engineer responsible for designing, developing, and supporting client applications, driving business growth.

- Developed and maintained nationwide educational platforms, enhancing the learning experience for thousands of users.
- Built a comprehensive financial management application with Laravel and Vue.
- Managed all DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup ensuring reliable and efficient deployment processes.
- → Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, MySgl, VueJS

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

PHP Application Developer at iQU Group (Amsterdam, NL)

Marketing solutions for game developers.

- Created complete APIs from start to end as well as libraries which were used by my colleagues.
- Another smaller project was built with Java and PipelineDB.
- → Technologies: PHP, Laravel, Symfony, API, MySQL, Git, Docker, CLI, PhpUnit, AngularJS, Java

Oct 2014 - Nov 2015

PHP Application Developer at Project 89109 (Amsterdam, NL)

Online dating services.

■ → Technologies: PHP, API, MySQL, CLI, Git, JS, jQuery.

Nov 2017 - Current

Hardware Engineer / Dev-Ops at Hidden Hash (Cluj-Napoca, RO)

Family business dealing with mining crypto-currencies.

- Worked on Business model, Legal compliance, setup, Software & security optimization/tweaks/updates,
 Performance fine tuning.
- Built an open-source watchdog mechanism: github.com/iosifv/amd-vega-startup-scripts

PROJECTS (3)

CLI Path

 Built a production-ready financial web application (originally a T3 Stack training project) to calculate recurring monthly expenses with a simple UI, multi-currency and cryptocurrency support, and an intuitive tagging system for organization.

(T3 Stack, NodeJS, NextJS, PostgreSQL, TailwindCSS, Vercel, GHA)

CLI Path

 Created a CLI tool to check Google Maps directions, with saved locations, authentication, and a custom serverless API layer to simplify token management — built for training, touching multiple technologies (NodeJs, Serverless Framework, AWS, Auth0, OpenAPI, VHS, npm, GHA)

Casa4 website

✓ https://casa4.co.uk/

An overengineered personal website built for learning purposes (Hugo, Terraform, Cloudfront, AWS, GHA)

EDUCATION (2)

2012 - 2010

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

Operations Management

Business Analytics Marketing Fundamentals Human Resource Management

Operations Management

2004 - 2009

Bachelor of Engineering Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca



INTERESTS

Hobbies

Motorcycles Photography
Chess HiFi Audio Boxing